There's more seats on the side.
늦게 들어오시는 분들은 측면에 더 많은 좌석이 있습니다.
people are walking in late. So, just to make sure you're in cs231n
이 수업은 CS231n
Deep Learning Neural network class for visual recognition.
Deep Learning Neural Network Class for Visual Recognition 입니다.
Anybody in the wrong class? OK, good. Alright. So, welcome and happy new year, happy first day of the winter break.
수업 잘못 들어오신 분 있나요? 좋아요. 환영합니다, 행복한 새해, 그리고 행복한 겨울 방학의 첫날 입니다.
So, this class CS231n. This is the second offering of this class
이 수업은 CS231n 의 두번째 개강입니다.
when we have literally doubled our enrollment from 180 people last time we offered to
우리는 지난 번에 180명의 수강생에서 이번엔 거의 350명으로
about 350 of you signed up. Just a couple of words to make us all legally
말 그대로 수강 인원을 두 배로 늘렸습니다.
covered, we are video recording this class. So, you know if you're
알아두셔야 할 것이 우리는 지금 동영상 촬영 중입니다.
uncomfortable about this for today just go behind that camera or go to the corner that
그러니 먄약 오늘 촬영이 불편하시면 카메라 뒤로 이동하거나
camera's not gonna turn, but we are going to send out forms for you to fill out in terms
카메라가 비추지 않는 쪽으로 이동하세요.
of allowing video recording. So, that's just one bit of housekeeping.
후에 동영상 촬영에 동의를 구하는 서류양식을 보내드릴겁니다.
So, alright. My name is Fei-Fei Li, a professor at the computer science department.
좋아요. 저는 컴퓨터 과학부의 교수이며 이름은 Fei-Fei Lee 입니다.
So, this class, I'm co-teaching with two senior graduate students and one of them
이 수업동안 제가 두 명의 대학원생과 함께 가르치는데,
is here. He's Andre Karpathy. Andre can you just say hi to everybody? We have.. I don't think Andre needs too much
그 중에 한명은 지금 이 자리에 있습니다. 안드레, 모두에게 인사하세요.
introduction. A lot of you probably know his work,
안드레에 대해서는 많은 소개가 필요 없을 듯 합니다. 많은 분들이 아마 그를 알고 있을 겁니다.
follow his blog, his Twitter follower.
그의 블로그나 트위터를 팔로우하면서 말이죠.
Andre has way more followers than I do. So, he's very popular. And also Justin Johnson who is still
안드레가 저 보다 팔로워수가 훨씬 많아요. 엄청 유명하죠.
traveling internationally but will be back in a few days. So, Andre and Justin
그리고 다른 한명 저스틴 존슨은 아직 여행중인데 며칠 내로 돌아올 겁니다.
will be picking up the bulk of the lecture teaching, and today I'll be giving
안드레와 저스틴이 상당한 양의 강의를 진행하게 됩니다.
a first lecture but as you probably can see that I'm expecting a newborn very soon,
오늘은 제가 첫 강의를 진행 하겠지만 보시다시피 제가 곧, 몇 주안에, 아기를 낳을 예정입니다.
speaking of weeks, so you'll see more of Andre and Justin in lecture time. We will
그래서 아마 여러분들은 안드레와 저스틴을 강의 시간에 더 많이 보게 될 것입니다.
also introduce a whole team of TAs towards the end of this lecture.
또한 강의를 마치기 전에 전체 조교들을 소개해 드릴 것입니다.
Again, people who are looking for seats you go out of that door and come back. There's
아직 좌석을 찾고있는 분은 밖으로 돌아서 들어오시면
a whole bunch of seats on the side. So, for this lecture, we're going to
저쪽에 자리가 많이 있습니다. 이 수업에서 우리는
give the introduction of the class, what kind of problems we work on and the
이 강좌에 대한 소개, 우리가 풀고있는 문제들과 도구들을 다룰 것입니다.
tools will be learning. So, again, welcome to CS231n. This is a vision class.
다시 한번, Vision 수업 CS231n 강의에 오신 것을 환영 합니다.
It's based on a very specific modeling architecture called neural network
이 수업은 매우 구체적으로 Neural Network 이라는 모델링 아키텍처를 다루게 되며
and the more specifically, mostly on the Convolutional Neural Network
더 자세히는 Convolutional Neual Network 을 다룹니다.
and a lot of you hear this term, maybe through a popular press article or
Deep Learning Network 이라고도 부르는 이 용어를 아마 언론매체 기사에서 접하게 될 텐데.
coverage we tend to call this the deep learning network. Vision is one of the fastest growing field of
Vision은 인공지능 분야에서도 제일 빠르게 성장하고 있는 분야중 하나입니다.
artificial intelligence. In fact, CISCO has estimated it and we are
실제로, CISCO사의 자료에 의하면,
day 4 of this by 2016 which we already have arrived more than 85% of
지금 이 시간, 2016의 4번째 날, 인터넷 사이버공간 데이터의 85% 이상이
the Internet cyberspace data is in the form of pixels
pixel 형태로 존재합니다.
or what they call Multimedia. So, we basically have entered at age of vision
멀티미디어라고 하죠. 우리는 다시말해 이미지들과 영상 - Vision의 시대에 들어 온 것입니다.
of images and videos. Why is this so, well partially to a large extent
비젼이 이렇게 큰 부분을 차지하는 이유는
is because of the explosion of both the Internet as a carrier of data as well as
데이터 캐리어로써의 인터넷과 센서들 덕분입니다.
sensors. We have more sensors than the number of people on the Earth these days.
우리는 이미 지구상의 인구수보다 많은 센서들을 가지고 있지요.
Every one of you is carrying some kind of smart phones, digital cameras and
모든 사람이 스마트 폰, 디지털 카메라를 가지고 있고
you know, cars running on the street with cameras. So, the sensors
길을 달리는 차들도 카메라가 있죠.
have really enabled the explosion of visual data on the Internet but visual
정말 센서들은 폭발적인 양의 시각 데이터를 인터넷으로 불러왔죠.
data or pixel data is also the hardest data to harness so if you have heard my
하지만 시각 데이터 또는 픽셀 데이터는 또한 가장 다루기 힘든 데이터입니다.
previous talks and some other talks by Computer Vision professors, we call this the dark matter of the Internet
저와 다른 Computer Vision 교수들은 시각 데이터를 인터넷의 암흑 물질이라고 부릅니다.
why is this the dark matter? Just like the universe consist of to 85% dark
왜 암흑 물질일까요? 이유는 바로 우주의 85%가 암흑 물질로 이루어져 있으며,
matter. Dark energy is these matters that energy that is very hard to observe.
이 암흑 에너지또한 아주 관측하기 어렵기 때문입니다.
we can infer it by mathematical models in the universe. On the Internet these are the
우리는 수학적 모델로써 암흑 에너지를 추론해 볼 수 있죠.
matters pixel data are the data that we don't know. We have a hard time
인터넷에서는 픽셀 데이터가 바로 우리가 잘 모르는, 우리가 내용을 알아내기 힘든 암흑물질인 것이죠.
grasping the contents here's one very very simple aspects for you to consider
여기에 여러분이 고려해야할 아주 간단한 측면이 있습니다.
so today
오늘
YouTube servers every 60 seconds we'll have more than 150 hours of videos uploaded
매 60초마다 유튜브 서버들로 150시간 이상되는 분량의 동영상이 업로드됩니다.
onto YouTube servers for every 60 seconds
메 60초마다.
Think about the amount of data. There is no way that human eyes can sift through
데이터의 양에 대해 생각해보면 인간의 눈으로는 이 방대한 데이터를
this massive amount of data and make it annotations,
가려내고
labeling it, and describe the contents. So, think from the
분류하여 내용을 묘사할 방법이 없습니다.
perspective of the YouTube team or Google company. If they want to help us
YouTube 팀이나 또는 Google 회사의 관점에서 생각해보면
to search, index, manage, and of course for their purpose,
그들이 이 데이터들을 검색하고 분류하고 또는 그들을 위한 광고를 넣고
put advertisement or whatever manipulate the content of the data, we're at a loss,
무엇을 하려고 하던지간에 이건 답이 없어요.
because nobody can hand-annotate this. The only hope we can do this is through vision
아무도 직접 손으로 분류를 할 수가 없기 때문이죠. 우리가 가진 유일한 희망은 Vision 기술입니다.
technology. To be able to label the objects, find the scenes, find the frames,
사물이나 풍경들을 알아내고
you know, locate where that basketball video were Kobe Bryant is making like that
코비 브라이언트가 끝내주는 슛을 날리는 농구 비디오를 찾아내는 거죠.
awesome shot. So, these are the problems that we are facing today that the
이런 것들이 지금 우리가 직면하고있는 문제들입니다.
massive amount of data and the challenges of the dark matter.
엄청난 양의 데이터, 즉 인터넷의 암흑 물질에 대한 도전이죠.
So, computer vision is a field that touches upon many other fields of
컴퓨터 비젼분야는 다른 많은 분야와 맞닿아 있습니다.
studies. So, I am sure that even sitting here,
마치 여기 앉아계신 여러분들 중에서도
many of you come from computer science, but many of you come from biology, psychology,
어떤 분들은 컴퓨터 과학에서, 어떤 분들은 생물학, 심리학,
are specializing in natural language processing or graphics or robotics or
자연어 처리, 그래픽스, 로보틱스,
or you know medical imaging and so on. So, as a field, computer vision is really a
또는 의료 영상등 여러분야에서 온것 처럼요. 컴퓨터 비전은 실제로
truly interdisciplinary field. What the problems we work on, the models we use
여러 학문이 관련된 분야있니다. 우리가 풀고있는 문제들, 사용하는 모델들은
touches an engineering, physics, biology, psychology computer science and mathematics.
물리학, 생물학, 심리학, 컴퓨터 과학과 수학까지 관련되어 있죠.
So just a little bit of a more personal touch, I am the director of the computer vision lab
좀 더 개인적인 이야기를 하자면, 저는 스탠포드에서 컴퓨터 비젼 연구실을 맡고 있는데요.
at the Stanford. In our lab, I work with graduate students and post-docs and even
대학원생, 박사후 연구원과
under-graduate students on the number of topics and most dear to our own research
학부생들까지 함께 우리의 연구를 위해 아주 많은 주제를 다룹니다.
who some of them, you know, Andre, Justin come from my lab.
그들 중 일부는 음.. 안드레와 저스틴도 우리 연구실에 있고요,
A number of TAs come from my lab. we work on machine learning which is part
많은 조교들도 우리 연구실 출신입니다. 우리는 머신러닝,
of a superset of deep learning. We work a lot on cognitive science and neuroscience as well
즉 딥러닝을 포함하는 큰 분야를 연구하며, 자연어 처리와 연설의 교차점으로서
as the intersection between an NLP and speech. so that's that's the kind of
인지과학과 신경과학에 대해서도 많은 연구를 합니다.
landscape of computer vision research that my lab works. So, also to put things
제 연구실에 대한 간략한 소개였습니다.
in a little more perspective, what other computer vision classes that we offer
자, 그럼 조금 다른 관점에서 생각해볼 수 있도록 어떠한 Vision 수업들이
here at Stanford through the computer science department. Clearly, you're in
스탠포드 컴퓨터 과학부에서 열리는지 알아보도록 하죠.
this class CS231n. So, some of you who have never taken computer vision
여러분들은 지금 CS231n 수업을 듣고 계시고요. 이 중에서 컴퓨터 비전수업을 한번도 들어 본 적이 없고
probably heard of computer vision for the first time. probably should have already
컴퓨터 비전이란 말을 처음 듣는 분들이 있다면
done CS131. That's an intro class of previous quarter we offered.
전 분기에 열었던 CS131 수업을 들으셨어야해요.
and then next quarter which normally is offered this quarter but this year as a
그리고 원래는 이번 분기에서 올해만 다음 분기로 미뤄진
little shifted there is an important graduate-level computer vision class
매우 중요한 대학원 수준의 컴퓨터 비젼 클래스
called CS231a offered by professor Silvio Savarese who works in robotic
CS231a 를 로보틱스 3D 비젼의 Silvio Savarese 교수가 가르칩니다.
3D vision and a lot of you ask the question that do these replace each other? CS231n versus
많은 분들이 CS231n 과 CS231a 수업이 서로 같은지 물어보시는데
CS231a and the answer is no. if you're interested in a broader
같지 않습니다. 만약 좀 더 넓은 범위의
coverage of tools and topics of computer vision as well as some of the
컴퓨터 비젼분야의 주제와 도구사용 및
fundamental topics that comes that related to 3D vision, robotic vision
3D 비젼, 로보틱스 비젼과 시각인지에 관한 기본적인 주제들에 관심이 있다면
and visual recognition you should consider taking 231a. That is the
더 포괄적인 231a 수업 수강을 고려해 보세요.
more general class. 231n which will go into starting today more deeply focuses
오늘부터 시작하는 231n은 좀 더 세부적인
on a specific ando of both problem and model. Model is neural network and the
문제와 모델을 다룹니다. 대부분 신경망 모델을 이용한
ando is visual recognition mostly, but of course they have a little bit of overlap but that's the major difference. Next quarter, we also have possibly
시각적 인식이죠. 당연히 두 수업에서
a couple of advanced seminar level class but that's still in the
심화된 수준의 세미나 수업이 몇몇 열릴 것 같아요. 하지만
formations so you just have to check the syllabus. So, that's the kind of computer
아직 미정이니 후에 강의목록을 확인하셔야 할겁니다.
vision curriculum we offer this year at Stanford. Any question so far? Yes
스탠포드 컴퓨터 비전 수업들을 대략적으로 소개했습니다. 질문있나요? 네.
131 is not a strict requirement for this class, but you should see that if you've
131이 이 수업의 선수과목은 아닙니다만,
never heard of computer vision for the first time I suggest you find a way to
컴퓨터 비전 수업을 처음 듣는다면
catch up because this class assumes a basic level of understanding of
이 수업은 컴퓨터 비전에대한 기본적인 이해를 요구하기 때문에
computer vision. You can browse the notes and so on.
강의노트 등을 통한 예습을 하길 권해드립니다.
Okay, so the rest of today is that I will give a very brief broad stroke history of computer vision
좋아요. 오늘은 컴퓨터 비전의 역사를 간단히 다루고
and then we'll talk about 231n little bit in terms of the organization
231n 수업이 어떻게 구성되어 있는지 이야기 해볼 것입니다.
of the class. I actually really care about sharing with you this brief history of computer
저는 사실 이 컴퓨터 비전의 역사를 다루는 것을 중요하게 생각하는데
vision because you know you might be here primarily because of your interest
여러분 대무분은 이 딥러닝이라는 매우 흥미있는 도구에 관심이 있어 이 자리에 있을텐데요,
in this really interesting tool called deep learning and this is the purpose of this
그것이 이 수업의 목적이기도 하고요.
class. We're offering you an in-depth look and then
이 수업은 딥러닝 모델이 무엇인지
and just journey through the of the what this deep learning model is but without
심도있게 다룰 것입니다.
understanding the problem domain, without thinking deeply about what this problem is,
하지만 문제가 속해있는 영역에 대한 이해, 문제에 대한 깊은 고찰없이는
it's very hard for you to to go out to be an inventor of the next model that
비젼분야의 새로운 문제를 해결하는
really solves the big problem in vision or to be you know developing developing
새로운 모델을 만들거나
making impactful work in solving a hard problem. and also in general problem
어려운 문제들을 푸는 일에 주요한 일을 하기 매우 어려울 것입니다.
domain and model the modeling tools themselves are never never fully
또한 일반적인 문제 영역과 모델링 도구 자체는
decoupled.
결코 완전히 서로 분리될 수 없어요.
They inform each other and you'll see through the history of deep learning a little
그들은 서로에게 정보를 제공합니다. 딥 러닝의 역사를 통해 알게 되겠지만
bit that the coalition on your network architecture come from the need to solve
네트워크 아키텍처의 연합은 비젼 문제들을 해결하고자 하는
a vision problem
필요에 의해 생겨납니다.
vision problem helps the the deep learning algorithm to evolve and I'm back and
그리고 다시 비전 문제는 딥 러닝 알고리즘을 발전시키는데 도움을 주게되죠.
forth so is really important to to you know I want you to finish this course I
그래서 매우 중요합니다. 여러분들이 이 수업을 마치고
feel proud that you're student of computer vision and of deep learning so you you
컴퓨터 비젼과 딥러닝 수업의 학생임을 자랑스러워 하길 바래요.
have this both tool-set and the in-depth understanding of how to use the
여러분들은 문제해결을 위한 도구들과 그 도구들을 사용하는 방법에 대한 깊은 이해를 갖게 될 거에요.
tool-set to to to to tackle important problems so it's a brief history but
도구는 간단한 역사 그래서 중요한 문제를 해결하기에에에 있지만,
does it mean so short history so we're gonna go all the way back to 200 540
우리가 거​​ (200) (540)에 다시 모든 길을 갈 것 때문에 그렇게 짧은 역사를 의미 하는가
million years ago so why why did I picked this you know on the other scale
왜 그랬는지이 고른 이유 만 년 전 그래서 당신은 다른 규모에 알고
of Earth history this is a fairly specific range of years while so I don't
그래서하지 않는 동안 지구 역사의이 년의 상당히 구체적인 범위는
know if you have heard of this but this is a very very curious period of the
이 들었을 알고 있지만 이것은 매우 호기심 기간
Earth's history biologists call this the big bag of evolution before 503
지구 역사의 생물 학자들은이 503 전에 진화의 큰 가방 전화
for 540 million years ago
5억4천만년 전을위한
a very peaceful of its pretty big pot of water so we have very simple organisms
물은 꽤 큰 냄비의 아주 평화로운 그래서 우리는 아주 간단한 생물이
these are like animals that just floats in the water and the way the eastern and
이건 그냥 물에 떠 동물과 방법 동부와 같다
now a daily basis is you know the flow to move some kind of food comes by near
지금은 매일 매일 당신이 음식 근처에 의해 제공의 어떤 종류를 이동하는 흐름을 알고있다
their house or whatever they just open their mouths grabbed it and we don't
그들은 단지 자신의 입을 열어 무엇이든 자신의 집 또는 그것을 잡고 우리는하지 않습니다
have too many different types of animals but really strange happened around 540
동물의 너무 많은 다른 유형을 가지고 있지만 정말 이상한 약 540 일
million solely from the fossils we study there's a huge explosive of species
전적으로 우리가 공부 화석에서 백만 종의 거대한 폭발있다
biologist car speciation like suddenly for some reason something that animal
어떤 이유로 어떤 동물을위한 갑자기 같은 생물학 차 분화
start to diversify and they got a complex the start 2022 you start a
다양 화하기 시작하고 그들이있어 복잡한 시작 2022 당신이 시작할
predators and praising and they have all kind of tools to to to survive what was
포식자와 찬양 그리고 그들은 무엇 살아남을 수있는 도구의 모든 종류가
the triggering force of those was a huge question because people received no did
사람들이 받았기 때문에 사람들의 트리거 힘이 큰 문제였다 더 않았다
you know another SAT whatever meteoroid earth or or you know the environment
당신은 어떤 유성 지구 또는 다른 SAT 알고하거나 환경을 알고
change they talk about one of the most convincing theory is by this guy call
그들이 가장 설득력있는 이론의 약 얘기를 변경하면이 사람의 전화입니다
Andrew Parker
앤드류 파커
largest in Australia from Australia he he studied a lot of fun
호주에서 가장 큰 호주에서 그는 그가 재미를 많이 공부
fossils and he's theory is that it was the onset of the ice so one of the first
화석 그 이론은 제 그렇게 한 얼음의 개시 인 것을
trial bites developed and I really really simple I it's almost like a
시험 물린 개발하고 정말 정말 간단 나는 그것은처럼 거의이다
pinhole camera that just catches light and make some projections in
단지 빛을 포착하고 몇 가지 예측을 핀홀 카메라
register some information from the environment
환경에서 일부 정보를 등록
suddenly life is no longer so medal because once you have that I the first
당신은 일단 때문에 갑자기 인생은 더 이상 이렇게 메달 없다 내가 처음 그
thing you can do is you could go patch for you actually know where food it's
음식이 어디 당신이 실제로 알고 당신이 할 수있는 것은 당신이 패치를 갈 수있다
not just like blind them floating in the water and was you can go cat food
뿐만 아니라 물에 떠있는 그들을 눈 멀게 좋아하고 당신이 고양이 먹이를 갈 수 있었다
guess what the food best better develop eyes and to run away from you otherwise
음식이 가장 좋은 눈을 개발하고, 그렇지 않으면 멀리에서 실행하는 것 같아요
they'll be gone you know your your so the first of all who had had eyes were
그들은 당신이 알고 사라질 것이다 당신의 눈을 가졌다 모든 사람의 첫 번째이었다 있도록
like in a limited both Google and so just like has the best time you think
그냥 좋아 제한된 구글 모두에서 그렇게 같은 것은 당신이 생각하는 가장 좋은 시간을 가지고
everything they can but because those are all set of lies what we what the
모든 것이 그들이 할 수 있지만, 그 거짓말 우리 것의 모든 설정을하기 때문에
college's realize is the biological arms race begin every single animal needs to
대학의 실현은 생물학적 군비 경쟁은 모든 단일 동물에 필요 시작이다
needs to learn to develop things to survive or to you know you you you
생존을 위해 일을 개발하기 위해 배울 필요가 또는 당신은 당신에게 당신이 알고에
suddenly have praised and predators and all this and the speciation so that's
즉, 그래서 갑자기 육식 동물이 모든과 분화와 칭찬했다
one vision begun 540 million years and not only religion begun visual was one
하나의 비전 540,000,000년 시작 및뿐만 아니라 종교는 시각적 시작 하나
of the major driving force of the speciation or that the big fan of
종 분화의 또는 큰 팬의 주요 원동력의
evolution or I so so we're not gonna fall evolution for with too much detail
진화 또는 정말 그래서 우리는 너무 많은 세부 사항에 대한 않을거야 가을의 진화있어
another big important work that the engineering of vision happened around
비전 엔지니어링 주위에 일어난 또 다른 큰 중요한 일
the Renaissance and of course it's attributed to this amazing guy so before
르네상스와는 물론 그 전에 너무 놀라운 사람에 의한 것
other songs you know throughout human civilization from Asia to Europe to
다른 노래는 유럽에 아시아에서 인류 문명에 걸쳐 알고
India to Arabic world we have seen models of cameras so Aristotle has
아리스토텔레스는이 때문에 인도는 아랍어 세계에 우리는 카메라의 모델을 보았다
proposed the camera through the Leafs Chinese philosopher moses have proposed
철학자 모세가 제안 잎을 중국어 통해 카메라를 제안
the camera through a box with the whole but
전체와 함께 상자를 통해 카메라 만
if you look at the first documentation really modern looking camera it's called
첫 번째 문서 정말 현대 찾고 카메라를 보면 그것이라고
camera obscura
카메라 옵스큐라
and that is documented by Leonardo da da Vinci I'm not gonna get into the details
그리고 그 레오나르도 다빈치에 의해 설명되어 나는 세부 사항에 들어갈 거 아니에요
but this is you know you get the idea that there is some kind of a whole to
그러나 이것은 당신이 전체의 몇 가지 종류가 존재한다는 생각을 알고있다
capture light reflected from the real world and then there is some kind of
캡처 빛이 현실 세계에서 반사 된 후 어떤 종류의가
protection to capture the information of the of the of the real-world image so
보호되도록 실제 이미지의의 정보를 캡처
that's the beginning of the modern you know engineering
즉, 당신이 알고있는 현대 엔지니어링의 시작이다
vision it started with one team to copy the world and wanted to make a copy of
비전이 세상을 복사 한 팀과 시작의 복사본을 만들고 싶었다
the visual world it hasn't gone anywhere close to wanting to engineer the
시각 세계는은을 설계하고자 어디서나 가까운 사라되지 않았습니다
understanding of the visual world right now we're just talking about duplicating
시각 세계의 이해는 지금 우리는 단지 복제에 대해 얘기하고
the visual world so that's one important work to remember and of course after
그래서 시각적 세계는 하나의 중요한 기억해야 할 일과 물론 이후의
camera obscura although we we we start to see a whole series of successful in
우리는 우리가 성공의 전체 시리즈를 참조하기 시작 우리하지만 카메라 옵스큐라
all some film gets developed you know like kodak was one of the first
모두가 어떤 영화는 코닥처럼 알고 개발되는 것은 최초의 일이었다
companies developing commercial cameras and then we start to have camcorders and
회사는 상업 카메라를 개발하고 우리는 캠코더를 가지고 시작
and and all this very important important piece of work that I want you
과 및 모든 작업이 매우 중요 중요한 부분 당신을 원하는
to be aware of as vision student is absolutely nothing engineering work but
비전 학생이 절대적으로 아무것도 엔지니어링 작품으로 알고 있어야하지만,
do you think science piece of science work that's starting to ask the question
당신은 질문을 시작하고 과학 연구의 과학 조각을 생각
is how does Visual work in our biological bring you know we
우리의 생물학적 비주얼 작업 당신이 우리를 알고 가져 않는 방법입니다
we now know that it took 540 million years of evolution to get to really
우리는 지금 정말에 도착하는 진화의 5억4천만년했다 것을 알고있다
fantastic visual system in humans but what did evolution do during this time
환상적인 비주얼 인간의 시스템 만 한 일이 진화는이 기간 동안 수행
what kind of architecture did develop from that simple trilobite to today
오늘 간단 삼엽충에서 건축의 어떤 종류를 개발 않았다
yours and mine while very important piece of work happened at Harvard lied
작업의 매우 중요한 부분 하버드에서 일어난 당신과 나의 동안 거짓말
to that time too young to very young ambitious pulls the occupant in the
그 시간에 야심 찬 아주 젊은 너무 젊은는에서 탑승자를 가져옵니다
vehicle what they did is that they used awake but anaesthetized cats and then
그들이 무슨 짓을했는지 차량은 다음 깨어 있지만 마취 고양이를 사용한다는 것입니다
there was not technology to build this little needle electrode to push the
를 밀어이 작은 바늘 전극을 구축하는 기술은 없었다
electrons through to the the the the skull is open until the bringing of the
상기하여 두개골을 통해 전자가의 지참까지 열려
cut into an area what we already know come primary visual cortex primary
우리는 이미 일차 시각 피질의 차를 올 알고있는 지역으로 절단
visual cortex area do a lot of things for for visual processing but before
시각 피질 영역은 영상 처리하지만, 전에 일을 많이 할
visa we don't really know what primary visual cortex is to be winter snow is
우리가 정말 모르는 비자는 시각 주요 내용 피질 겨울 눈이 될 것입니다
one of the earliest stage of the UI is of course but earliest stage for visual
사용자 인터페이스의 초기 단계 중 하나는 물론이지만 시각에 대한 초기 단계
processing then there is tons and tons of new orleans working on vision then we
처리는 다음의 비전에 우리 작업 톤 뉴 올리언스의 톤이있다
really alter our to know what this is because that's the beginning of vision
그 비전의 시작이기 때문에 정말이 무엇인지 알고 우리를 변경
visual process in the bring so they they put this electrode into the primary
(가) 그렇게 가져 시각 과정은 그들이 차에이 전극을 넣어
visual cortex and an interesting this is another interesting fact I don't drop my
시각 피질이 흥미로운 내가 떨어 뜨리지 않는 또 다른 흥미로운 사실​​ 내
stuff for sure you probably visual cortex the first they come from being
(가) 첫째가되는 것을 온 있는지 아마 시각 피질에 대한 물건
very very rough prosecutor first aid of your cortical visual processing stage is
당신의 대뇌 피질의 시각 처리 단계의 아주 아주 거친 검사 응급 처치입니다
in the back of your bring not near your I know it's very interesting because
당신이 근처에없는 가져 뒷면에 나는 그것이 있기 때문에 매우 흥미로운 알고
your own factory in cortical processing is right
대뇌 피질의 처리에 자신의 공장이 맞다
behind her nose your auditory is right behind every year but your primary
그녀의 코 뒤에 청각 바로 매년 그러나 주 뒤에
visual cortex is the furthest from your eye and another very interesting that in
시각 피질은 눈에서 가장 먼과에서 그 또 다른 매우 흥미로운 일이다
fact not only the primary there's a huge area working on vision almost 50% of
사실뿐만 아니라 기본 비전 거의 50 %의 작업 거대한 지역에있다
your brain is a love division this in this the hardest and most important
당신의 두뇌는이이 어려운 가장 중요한 사랑의 부서입니다
sensory perceptual cognitive system in the break and I'm not saying anything
감각 지각인지 휴식 시간에 시스템 난 아무것도 말하고 있지 않다
else does is not useful clearly but it take nature of this long to develop this
다른 않습니다 분명히 도움이되지 않습니다하지만이 개발이 긴의 특성을
this sensory system and it takes the troop this much realist a space to be
이 감각 시스템은 그것을 할 병력에게 공간이 많은 현실 소요
used for the system why because it's so important and it's so damn hard that's
너무 중요하기 때문에 왜 시스템에 사용 그렇게 빌어 먹을 하드 그건입니다
why we need to get back to human reason they were really ambitious they wanna
우리는 인간의 이성을 다시 얻을 필요가 왜 그들이 싶어 정말 야심했다
know what primary visual cortex is doing because this is the beginning of our
이의 시작이기 때문에 일차 시각 피질이 무엇을하고 있는지 알고 우리의
knowledge for deep learning neural network cats social then put the cats in
다음 소셜 깊은 학습 신경망 고양이에 대한 지식에 고양이를 넣어
this room and they were recording your activities when I say recording your
나는 당신의 기록 말할 때이 방은 그들이 당신의 활동을 기록했다
activities fair trial there basically trying to see you know if I put the
내가 넣어 경우 활동 공정한 재판이 기본적으로 당신이 알고 보려고
electrode here like to the new office to the new house fire when they see
여기에 새로운 사무실 등 그들이 볼 수있는 새 집 화재 전극
something so for example if they show if they show cat their ideas if I showed
그래서 예를 들어 뭔가 내가 보여 주었다 경우 그들이 자신의 아이디어를 고양이를 보여 주면 그들이 보여 주면
this kind of fish you know apparently at that time comes to eat fish rather than
당신이 그 때 분명히 알고 물고기의이 종류보다는 물고기를 먹고 온다
these beings with the cats no I like yellow happy and spikes and here's a
여기에 노란색 행복과 스파이크와 같은 더 나는 없다 고양이와 함께이 존재
story of scientific discovery is scientific discovery takes both luck and
과학적 발견의 이야기는 과학적 발견이 소요 행운 모두와
care and thoughtfulness they were shown
관심과 배려 그들은 나타내었다
whatever mouse flower it just doesn't work the cats new are in the primary
어떤 마우스 꽃 단지 새로운 고양이를 작동 차에하지 않습니다
visual cortex was silent there was no spiking
시각 피질은 급상승가 없었다 침묵
very little spike in there were really frustrated but the good news is that
거기에 약간의 스파이크 정말 좌절했다 그러나 좋은 소식은 있다는 것입니다
there was no computer at that time so what they have to do when they showed us
그들이 우리를 보였다 때이해야 할 무엇 때문에 그 시간에는 컴퓨터가 없었다
cats is they have to use a slight protector so they put his foot a slide
고양이는 그들이 그의 발 슬라이드 넣을 수 있도록 약간의 보호를 사용해야 할 것이다
of a fish and then wait till the new on Spike if the new imposes bike they take
새로운 강요하며 자전거가 걸릴 경우 물고기의 다음 스파이크에 새로운까지 기다려
the slide out putting another slight
슬라이드 아웃 다른 약간을 넣어
notice I would have liked this like you know this film I don't you remember to
이 영화는 내가 당신이 기억하지 알고처럼이 좋아하는 것주의 사항
use glasser film whatever the Douro spikes that's weird you know like the
당신이처럼 알고 이상한 그 무엇이든 도우루가 스파이크 래셔 필름을 사용
actual mouse official flower didn't drive the new excite the new role but
실제 마우스 공식 꽃 새가 새 역할을 자극 운전하지 않았지만
the the the movement of taking the slide out nor could he has sliding did excite
상기 아웃 슬라이드를 복용의 이동도 그는 흥분 않았다 슬라이딩 한 수
the new I can be the catalyst think you'll finally they're changing the new
나는 촉매가 될 수있는 새로운 당신이 마침내 새를 변경하는 것 같아요
you know new objects for me so it turned out there is created by this life that
그것은이 생활에 의해이 생성되어 있도록 나를 위해 새로운 객체를 알고
they're changing right slide the whatever it's a square rectangular plate
그들은 그것이 정사각형, 직사각형 판이야 무엇이든 바로 슬라이드를 변경하고
and that moving edge or excited the nuance so they're really taste the after
것을 에지 또는 흥분 뉘앙스를 이동 그들은 정말 후 맛을하고 그래서
that observations you know if they were too frustrated or to have missed that
너무 좌절하거나 놓친 것 인 경우에 관찰 당신은 알고
but they're not the they're really taste after that and realize new songs in the
하지만 그들은 그들이 정말로 그 후 맛과 새로운 노래를 실현하고 아니에요
primary visual cortex are organized in columns and for every column of the new
차 시각 피질은 열에 새의 모든 컬럼에 대해 구성되어 있습니다
Alice they'd like to see a specific orientation of the of the bars rather
앨리스는이 바의 특정 방향을 오히려보고 싶습니다
than the Fisher a mouse
피셔 마우스보다
you know I'm a bit of a simple story because there are still numerous in
당신은 여전히​​ 수많은 있기 때문에 나는 간단한 이야기​​ 좀 해요 알고
primary visual cortex we don't know what they like they don't like simple
차 시각 피질 우리는 그들이 단순한 마음에 안 좋아하는지 모르겠어요
oriented but by large with a human visitor found that the beginning of
지향하지만 인간의 방문자 대형하여 처음의 발견
visual processing is not a holistic fish or malice the beginning of visual
시각 처리는 전체적인 생선이나 악의 시각의 시작되지 않습니다
processing is simple structures of the world
처리는 세계의 간단한 구조입니다
oriented and this is a very deep deep implications are signs as well as
배향이 매우 깊은 깊이 영향뿐만 아니라 징후이며
engineering modeling it's later when we visualize our dealer network features
우리는 우리의 딜러 네트워크 기능을 시각화 할 때 엔지니어링 모델링은 나중에 야
will see that simple like structure in emerging from our from our model and
우리의 모델 우리에서 신흥 구조 등의 간단한 표시되고
even though the discovery was later fifties and early sixties they won the
발견했다하더라도 나중에 쉰과 60 년대 초반은 그들이 원
nobel medical price for this work in 1981 so that was another very important
1981 년이 작품에 대한 노벨 의학 가격은 그래서 또 다른 매우 중요
piece of work related to vision and visual processing so that's another
즉 다른, 그래서 작품의 조각의 비전과 시각적 처리와 관련된
interesting story the precursor of computer vision as a modern field was
재미있는 이야기 현대 필드와 컴퓨터 비전의 전구체이었다
this particular dissipation by Larry Roberts in 1963 it's called block world
이 블록의 세계라고 1963 년 래리 로버츠에 의해이 특정 손실
he just as humulin visa we're discovering that the visual world in our
그는 단지 휴 물린 비자로 우리의 시각 세계 있음을 발견하고 우리의
brain is organized by simple like structures Larry Roberts as early as PhD
뇌는 빠르면 박사와 같은 구조 래리 로버츠처럼 간단한에 의해 구성되어있다
students were trying to extract these like structures
학생들은 다음과 같은 구조를 추출하고있었습니다
images
이미지
as a as a piece of engineering work in this particular case his goal is that
이 특정한 경우에 엔지니어링 작업의 조각 같은 그의 목표는 것입니다
you know both you and not as humans can recognize blocks no matter how it's
당신은 모두 당신을 알고 인간은 아무리 그것이 얼마나 블록을 인식 할 수 없습니다하지로
turned right like we know it's a saint block these two are the same block even
우리가 성자 블록이 두 알고 같은 블록도 있습니다 오른쪽과 같이 설정
though the lighting changed and the orientation changed and he's conjuncture
조명이 변화하고 있지만 방향이 변경 그는 국면이다
is that just like we thought told us it's the edges that define this the
우리가 우리에게 생각하는 것처럼이 이것을 정의 가장자리는 것이다
structure that the edges defying the laws shape and they don't change
구조 가장자리가 법률의 형태를 무시하고는 변경하지 않는 것이
relevant all these internal things so Larry Roberts Road a PhD dissertation to
래리 로버츠 도로 박사 학위 논문에 아주 관련된 모든 내부 물건
just extract these edges you know if your work as a PhD student computer
그냥 있는지 알이 가장자리를 추출 박사 과정 학생 컴퓨터로 작업
vision this is like you know this is like undergraduate computer vision would
이 학부 컴퓨터 비전처럼 알처럼이 비전은 것
have been had PhD theses but that was the first precursor computer vision PhD
박사 학위 논문을했지만, 즉 제 1 전구체 컴퓨터 비전 박사이었다되었습니다
theses like Robert since interest he gave up his computer vision afterwards
그는 이후 자신의 컴퓨터 비전을 포기 관심 때문에 로버트 같은 논문
and DARPA I was one of the inventors of the internet we didn't do too badly by
과 DARPA는 내가 너무 심하게하여 우리가하지 않은 인터넷의 발명자 중 하나였다
giving up computer vision but we always like to say that the birth of computer
컴퓨터 비전을 포기하지만 우리는 항상 좋아하는 말을 해당 컴퓨터의 탄생
vision as a modern field is in the summer of 1966 the summer of 1966 MIT
현대 필드와 비전은 1966 년 여름에 1966 MIT의 여름
artificial intelligence lab was established before that actually for one
인공 지능 연구소는 하나 실제로 그 전에 설립되었다
piece of history should feel proud of them for student this there are two
역사의 조각이 학생에 대한 그들의 자부심을 느껴야한다이 두 가지가 있습니다
pioneering artificial intelligence lab established in the world in the early
초기에 세계에 설립 선구적인 인공 지능 연구실
1960's one by Marvin Minsky at MIT one by John McCarthy at suffered a stone for
존 맥카시에 의해 MIT 하나에서 마빈 민스키에 의해 1960 년대 하나에 돌에 대한 고통
the artificial intelligence lab was established before the computer science
인공 지능 연구실은 컴퓨터 과학 전에 설립되었다
department and professor John McCarthy who founded and I love is the one who is
설립 내가 사랑하는 부서 및 교수 존 맥카시는 하나입니다
responsible for
에 대한 책임
the term artificial intelligence so that's a little bit of a problem
그 문제의 조금 그래서 용어 인공 지능
stempler history but anyway we have to give us credit for starting the field of
stempler 역사 어쨌든 우리는 분야를 시작하는 우리에게 신용을 제공해야
computer vision because in the summer of 1966 a professor at MIT I decided it's
컴퓨터 비전이 때문에 1966 년 여름에 MIT의 교수 나는 그것의 결정
time to salvage you know so I was established we will start to understand
시간은 그래서 우리가 이해하기 시작 설립되었다 알고 구제하기
I think this proves probably invented at that time but anyway
나는 이것이 아마 그 시간에 어쨌든 발명 입증한다 생각
vision is so easy you open your eyes you see the world how can this be love one
비전 당신이 당신의 눈을 너무 쉽게 열려있는이 사랑의 하나가 될 수있는 방법을 세상을보고
summer so
여름 그래서
so the summer vision project is an attempt to use our visual system this
그래서 여름 비전 프로젝트는 우리의 시각 시스템이 사용하기위한 시도이다
was the proposal from last number and maybe they didn't use their summer work
마지막 번호의 제안이었다 어쩌면 그들은 그들의 여름 작업을 사용하지 않은
effectively but in any case how individual was not solved in that silver
효과적으로하지만 어떤 경우에 어떻게 개인이 그 실버 해결되지 않았다
since then they become the fastest growing field of computer vision and I
그 이후로 그들은 컴퓨터 비전 및 I의 가장 빠르게 성장하는 분야가 될
if you go to today's premium computer vision conferences cost CPR or ICC we we
오늘의 프리미엄 컴퓨터 비전 컨퍼런스에 가면 CPR 또는 우리 ICC 비용
have like 2000 to 2500 researchers worldwide attending this conference and
2000 2500에 대한 연구가 전 세계적으로이 회의에 참석처럼 가지고
very practical note 44 students if you are a good computer vision / machine
매우 실용적인 노트 (44) 학생 당신은 좋은 컴퓨터 비전 / 기계 경우
learning students you will not worry about jobs in Silicon Valley or or
학생들이 학습 당신은 실리콘 밸리 나 또는 작업에 대해 걱정하지 않습니다
anywhere else so it's actually one of the most exciting field but that was the
다른 곳에서는 실제로 가장 흥미로운 분야 중 하나입니다하지만 그래서이었다
birth of computer vision which means this year is the fiftieth anniversary of
올해 의미 컴퓨터 비전의 탄생의 50 주년입니다
computer vision that's a very exciting year in computer vision I we have a
우리가이 컴퓨터 비전 I에서 매우 흥미로운 년의 컴퓨터 비전
caller who long long way
발신자 사람 오래 오래 방법
ok so continued of computer vision
확인 그래서 컴퓨터 비전의 계속
this is a person to remember David Mark he he was also at MIT at that time
이 그가 그가 그 시간에 MIT에서도했다 데이비드 마크를 기억하는 사람
working with a number of shimon tommy tommy pope Jill and Mark himself died
사망 시몬 토미 토미 교황 질 마크 자신의 번호와 작업
early in the seventies very influential book called vision it's a very book
초기 70 년대의 비전라는 매우 영향력있는 책은 매우 책입니다
smart thinking about vision he took a lot of insights from your signs where he
비전에 대한 스마트 생각 그는 당신의 표지판 통찰력을 많이했다 그가 어디
said that he want reasonable give us the concept of simple structure regions
그는 우리에게 단순한 구조 영역의 개념을 제공 합리적인한다고 말했다
start with
시작
simple structure in today and start with a holistic fish or holistic not was mark
오늘의 간단한 구조와 전체적인 물고기로 시작하거나 전체적인 마크 아니었다
give us the next important insight and these two inside together is the
함께 인 우리에게 다음으로 중요한 통찰력과 두 내부를 제공
beginning of deep learning architecture is that vision is hierarchical you know
그 비전은 깊은 학습 아키텍처입니다 시작하는 당신이 알고있는 계층이다
so you will have easily said ok we start simple but this major world is extremely
그래서 당신은 쉽게 말한 것입니다 확인 우리는 간단하게 시작하지만,이 세계 주요 매우입니다
complex in fact I take a picture a regular picture today with my eiffel
사실 복잡한 내 에펠 오늘 사진을 일반 사진을 촬영
there is no my iPhone's resolution let's suppose it's like turned up exhaust the
내 아이폰의 해상도의 그것의 같은 켜져를 배기를 가정하자 전혀 없다
potential combination of pixels or picture in that is bigger than the total
그 픽셀 또는 그림의 잠재적 인 조합은 전체보다 크다
number of atoms in the universe that's how complex vision can be is it's it's
얼마나 복잡한 비전의 우주에있는 원자의 수는 그것의의입니다
really really complex human beings are told us they are simple David Mark told
정말 정말 복잡한 인간은 간단한 데이비드 마크는 이야기입니다 우리에게있다
us build a hierarchical model of course there mark didn't tell us to build it in
우리는 물론 계층 적 모델을 구축이 마크에 구축 알려하지 않았다
the coalition on your network which will cover for the rest of the quarter but
분기의 나머지 다룰 것 네트워크의 연합 있지만,
his ideas is to represent or to think about it image we think about it in
자신의 아이디어를 표현하기 위해 또는 우리가 그것에 대해 생각하는 이미지 그것에 대해 생각하는 것입니다
several layers the first one he thinks we should think about that edge image
여러 레이어 그는 우리가 그 가장자리 이미지에 대해 생각해야한다고 생각 첫 번째
which is clearly an inspiration noted took the inspiration from these oh and
이는 분명히 영감이 주목 오 이들로부터 영감을 가져다가
he personally called this the primal sketch
그는 개인적으로이 시원 스케치라고
you know the name is Sophie explain it
당신의 이름은 소피가 그것을 설명 알고
explained every now and then you think about one-half the this is work you
모든 이제 다음은이 작업이 약 1/2 생각 설​​명
start to Rick reconcile your 2d image with the 3d world you recognize there is
당신이 인식 3D 세계로 2D 이미지를 조정 릭에 시작
layers right I look at you right now I don't think half of you only has upheld
레이어 바로 지금 당장 당신의 절반 만지지하고있다 생각하지 않는다 당신을보고
in the neck
목
even though that's all I see there is I know you're all concluded by the row in
그게 내가이 표시되는 모든 비록 당신이 모든 행에 체결 거 알아
front of you and this challenge will post problem to solve
당신이 문제의 전면 해결하기 위해 문제를 게시 할 예정입니다
nature had that you oppose prob to solve because the broadest 3d imagery 2d
자연은 광범위한 차원 이미지의 2D 때문에 해결하기 위해 확률값 반대하는 것으로했다
nature saw that my first a hard work trick we just to ice it did they use one
자연은 내 첫 번째 하드 작업 트릭은 우리가 그들이 하나를 사용했던 아이스하는 것을보고
I but there's gonna be a whole bunch of hoes software trick to lurch the
I하지만 거 야를 돌출하는 괭이 소프트웨어 트릭의 전체 무리가있을 수있어
formation of the two eyes and Aldous so the same thing with computer vision we
컴퓨터 비전과 같은 일 때문에 두 눈의 형성과 더스 우리
have to solve that too and have tea problem and they eventually we have to
그것도를 해결하고 차에 문제가있는 그리고 그들은 결국 우리에게있다
put everything together so that we actually have a good 3d model of the
우리가 실제로 좋은 3D 모델을 함께 있도록 모든 것을 넣어
world why do we have to have a 3d model of the world as we have to survive
세계는 왜 우리가 살아남을 가지고 우리가 세계의 3D 모델을해야합니까
navigate manipulate the world when I shake your hand I really need to know
나는 손을 흔들 때 내가 정말 알아야 할 세계를 조작 이동
how do you know
당신은 알고 어떻게
external my hand and grab your heading the right way that is a 3d modeling of
내 손을 외부와가의 3 차원 모델링입니다 올바른 방법을 향하고 잡아
the world otherwise I won't be able to grab your head in the right way when I
세계 그렇지 않으면 나는 때 올바른 방법으로 당신의 머리를 잡아 할 수 없습니다
pick up a mug the same thing so so that's that's that's David Marr's
그건 그래서, 그래서 그 데이비드 마르의의 찻잔에게 같은 일을 데리러
architecture for vision that's a high-level abstract architecture it
높은 수준의 추상적 인 아키텍처의 비전 아키텍처 그것을
doesn't really inform us exactly what kind of mathematical modeling we should
정말 수학적 모델링 정확히 어떤 종류의 정보를 통보하지 않습니다 우리는해야
it doesn't inform us of the learning procedure and they really does the
그것은 학습 과정의 정보를 통보하지 않으며, 그들은 정말 않습니다
inference procedure which we will getting to through the deep learning
우리는 깊은 학습을 통해에 도착합니다 추론 절차
that word architecture but that's not that's the high-level view of important
그 단어 아키텍처하지만이 아닌 그의 중요의 높은 수준의보기이다
it's an important concept to learn
그것은 배울 수있는 중요한 개념이다
envisioned and we call this the
구상 우리는 이것을 호출
representation really important work and this is a little bit stuff first trip to
표현 정말 중요한 작업 및이에 약간의 물건 첫번째 여행이다
just show you as soon as they lead out this important way of thinking about the
다만 즉시이에 대해 생각이 중요한 방법을지도로 보여
first wave of visual recognition algorithms went after the 3d model
영상 인식 알고리즘의 첫 번째 물결은 3D 모델 이후 갔다
because that's the goal right like no matter how you represent the stages the
그 오른쪽에 상관없이 같은 목표이기 때문에 어떻게 단계을 나타냅니다
goal here is to reconstruct recognized object and this is really sensible
여기에 목표는 인식 개체를 복원하는 것입니다이 정말 합리적이다
because that's when we go to the world and do so both of these to your work
우리는 당신의 일에 그렇게 이들 모두를 세계로 이동 할 때이 있기 때문에
comes from Palo Alto one of those from sum 41 as far as ROI Sao Tome before was
팔로 알토 (Palo Alto)에서 유래 합계 41까지로 투자 수익 (ROI) 상투 메에서 그 중 하나는 예전
a professor at Stanford
스탠포드 교수
I love that he and his two directly Brooks proposed 11 of the first
나는 그와 그의이 직접 브룩스가 처음으로 11을 제안 사랑
so-called generalized till salu model I'm not gonna get into the details but
살루 모델까지 일반화 된 소위 아니에요거야 세부 사항에 들어가 있지만,
the idea is that the world is composed of simple shapes like
아이디어는 세상이 같은 간단한 형태로 구성되어 있다는 것입니다
wonders blocks and then any real world object is just a combination of these
블록을 궁금해하고 실제 세계의 객체는이 단지 조합
simple shapes given the particular feeling and go and that was a very
간단한 형태는 특정 느낌을 주어 이동이 매우이었다
influential visual recognition model in the seventies and went on to become the
70 년대 영향력있는 시각적 인식 모델이되기 위해 계속
Director of MIT lab and he was also a founding member of iRobot company rumba
MIT 연구소의 이사 그는 또한 아이 로봇 회사 룸바의 창립 멤버였다
and all this so so he continued the very influential
이 모든 그래서 그래서 그는 매우 영향력을 계속했다
I work and nobody interesting model coming from local
나는 일을하고 아무도 흥미로운 모델은 지역에서 오는
Research Institute I think I saw I is across the street from El Camino is this
연구소는 나는 엘 카미노이 인에서 나는 길 건너 본 것 같아요
pictorial structure model has less of a 3d flavor but more of a probabilistic
화보 구조 모델은 확률의 차원 맛이 덜하지만 더있다
flavor is that the objects are made of a still simple part
맛은 개체가 여전히 간단한 부분 만들어진 것입니다
like a person's head is made of eyes and nose or mouth and the parts were CuMn
같은 사람의 머리는 눈, 코 또는 입 만들어진 부품은 CuMn되어 있었다
acted by springs allowing for some deformations getting a sense of ok we
확인 우리의 감각을 받고 일부 변형을 허용 스프링에 의해 행동
recognize the world not every one of you have exactly the same eyes in the
세계를 인식하지 당신의 모든 하나는 정확히 같은 눈을 가지고
distance between the eyes will allow for some kind of rare variability so this
눈 사이의 거리 때문에이 드문 변화의 어떤 종류의 수
concept of variability start to get introduced in the model like this and
변화의 시작의 개념이 같은 모델에 도입하려면 및
using models like this you know the reason I want to show you this is too to
이가 너무 나는 당신을 보여주고 싶은 이유를 알고이 같은 모델을 사용하여
see how simple the the worst was a tease this was one of the most influential
표시 방법 애타게이 있었던 최악의 단순 가장 영향력있는 중 하나였다
model in the eighties recognizing real-world objects and the entire paper
실제 개체와 전체 용지를 인식하는 80 년대 모델
of real world is these seemingly users but the using the edges and simple
실세계의이 겉보기 사용자이지만 모서리를 사용하여 간단한
shapes warm but edges to to recognize this by another and other stuff or
따뜻한 모양이지만 서로 다른 재료 또는하여이를 인식하는 에지
graduate so that's that's that's kind of the incident world of computer vision
졸업 그건 그래서 그 컴퓨터 비전의 입사 세계의 종류의의
will wind up being seen black and white or even synthetic images started the
바람 것은 흑백 또는 합성 이미지가 시작 본적이되고
nineties we're finally started moving to like color images of real world and it
구십 우리는 마침내 컬러 현실 세계의 이미지를 좋아하는 이동하기 시작하고
was a big change again very very influential work here is not
다시 큰 변화 여기 매우 매우 영향력있는 작업이되지이었다
particularly about recognizing an object is about how do it like carve out an
객체를 인식하는 것은 대해 특히에 대해 어떻게은을 개척 좋아합니까
image into sensible parts right so if you enter this room there's no way your
당신이이 방을 입력하면 합리적인 부분으로 이미지를 바로 그래서 방법 당신이 없습니다
visual system is tell you of my god I see so many pics it was only have group
시각 시스템은 단지 그룹이되었다 내가 이렇게 많은 사진을 볼 세상에 당신을 말할 것입니다
things you see heads heads have territory chair a stage platform piece
일이 당신은 헤드 헤드 영토 의자 무대 플랫폼 조각이 참조
of furniture in the oldest this is called perceptual grouping perceptual
가구이 가장 오래된에 지각 그룹화 지각이라고
grouping as one of me
나 중 하나로 그룹화
most important problem envision biological or artificial if we don't
우리가하지 않으면 가장 중요한 문제는 생물학적 또는 인공 구상
know how to solve the perceptual grouping problem where they have a
그들은이 지각 그룹핑 문제를 해결하는 방법을 알고
really hard time to to deeply understand the visual world and you aren't words
정말 하드 시간은 깊이 시각적 세계를 이해하고 단어 수 없습니다
that end of this class this course a problem as fundamental as the still not
정지하지으로 기본이 수업이 과정에 문제의 끝
solved in computer vision even though we have made a lot of progress before
우리는 많은 진전 이전을 한 경우에도 컴퓨터 비전에 해결
departing after deplaning we're still grasping the final solution to a problem
우리는 여전히 문제로 최종 솔루션을 파악하고 deplaning 이후에 출발하는
like this so so this is again I why I want to give you at this introduction to
나는이 소개에서 당신을주고 싶어 왜이 같은 그래서 이것은 다시 I입니다
for you to be aware of the deep problems evasion and also the then-current they
당신은 또한 깊은 문제를 회피하고 당시 알고 있어야하는 그들은
in the the the the challenges envision we cannot solve all the problems despite
에 상기 도전 우리에도 모든 문제를 해결할 수없는 구상
whatever the noose s you know like we're far from developing terminators who can
올가미는 우리가 개발 터미네이터에서 멀리있는 것처럼 당신이 알고있는이야 어떤 사람 수
do everything so this piece of work is called normalized cut is what is one of
모든 것을 할 일이 조각이 정상화 컷이라고 있도록 중 하나입니다 무엇인가
the first computer vision work that takes real world images and tries to
에 실제 이미지와 시도 걸리는 최초의 컴퓨터 비전 작업
solve the problem is the senior computer vision researcher now professor at
고위 컴퓨터 비전 연구원이 교수에 지금 문제를 해결
berkeley also stanford graduate
버클리 또한 스탠포드 졸업
the results are not great I will not cover any sedimentation in this class
결과는 내가이 클래스의 모든 침전을 포함하지 않습니다 좋은하지 않습니다
from where you see we are making progress but this is the beginning of
당신이 보는 곳에서 우리는 진전이 있지만, 이것은의 시작입니다
that another very casual work that I want to i want to bring up and pay
불러 및 지불 내가하고 싶은 또 다른 매우 캐주얼 작업이 원하는
tribute for even though these work we're not covering them in the rest of the
비록이 작품에 대한 찬사 우리는의 나머지 부분을 커버하지 않는
course but I think it has a vision student pretty important for you to be
물론하지만 난 당신이 될 꽤 중요한 비전 학생이 생각
aware of this because not only introduces the important problem we want
이 알고 있기 때문에뿐만 아니라 우리가 원하는 중요한 문제를 소개합니다
to solve it also gives you a perspective of the development of the field let's
그것을 해결하는 것은 또한 당신에게 필드하자의 발전의 관점을 제공합니다
work is called villa jones face detector
작업이 호출 빌라 존스 얼굴 검출기
it's very dear to my heart because as a graduate student fresh graduate student
이 때문에 대학원생 신선한​​ 대학원 학생으로 내 마음을 매우 사랑이다
at cal tech it's the one of the first papers I read as a graduate student when
칼 테크에서 그것은 내가 대학원생 때과 같이 첫 번째 논문의 하나
I until the lab and I didn't know anything about it my advisers with this
나는이 내 고문 그것에 대해 아무것도 모르는 내가 실험실까지
amazing piece of work that you know we're all trying to understand them by
당신은 우리 모두가 그들을 이해하려는 알고 작품의 놀라운 조각
the time I graduated from Celtic this very work is transferred to the first
내가 셀틱 졸업 시간이 매우 작품은 처음에 전달된다
smart digital camera by Fujifilm in 2006 as the first digital camera that has a
이 최초의 디지털 카메라와 같은 2006 년에 후지 필름에 의해 스마트 디지털 카메라
face detector so far my transfer pump technology transfer point of view it was
보기의 얼굴 검출기 지금까지 내 이송 펌프 기술 이전 시점이되었다
extremely fast and there was one of the first successful high-level visual
매우 빠르고 시각적 첫 번째 성공적인 높은 수준의 일이 있었다
recognition algorithm that's being used by consumer product so let's work just
소비자 제품에 사용되고 인식 알고리즘 그래서 그냥 작업 할 수
learns to detect faces and faces in the wild with no longer soon you know
얼굴을 감지 배운다 더 이상 빨리 당신이 알고 함께 야생에서 직면하지
simulation they are a very contrived a these are any pictures and even though
시뮬레이션 그들은 매우 이들은 비록 모든 사진 및 있습니다 고안되어
he didn't use a deep learning network it has a lot of the deep learning flavor
그는 깊은 학습 풍미를 많이 갖는 깊은 학습 네트워크를 사용하지 않은
the features were learned the algorithm learns to find features simple features
기능은 기능을 간단한 기능을 찾을 수있는 알고리즘을 배운다을 알게되었다
like these black and white filter features that can you give us the best
당신이 우리에게 가장 좋은 줄 수있는이 흑백 필터 기능 등
localization of faces so this is a very influential piece of work it's also one
얼굴의 현지화 그래​​서 이것은 하나의 작품의 매우 영향력있는 작품이다
of the first computer visual work that is deployed computer and can roam real
컴퓨터를 배포하고 실제 로밍 할 수있는 첫 번째 컴퓨터 영상 작품의
time before that comparison algorithms were very slow the the paper actually is
그 비교 알고리즘 전에 시간은 용지가 실제로 매우 느린했다
called real-time face detection it was granted send him to tips I don't know if
이 부여 된 실시간 얼굴 인식이라고 나는 알고하지 않는 팁에 그를 보내
anybody remember that kind of chip but it was not a slow chat but nevertheless
사람이 칩의 종류를 기억하지만 느린 채팅 아니었지만 그럼에도 불구하고
it run real time that was another very important piece of art and also one more
그것은 또 다른 매우 중요한 예술 작품도 한 번 더 있었다 실시간으로 실행
thing to point out around this time this is not the only work
일이 유일한 일없는이시기에 지적하는
but this is a a really good representation Morales time the focus of
그러나 이것은 금주 모임 정말 좋은 표현 모랄레스 시간의 초점이다
computer vision is shifting remember that they've Mr
컴퓨터 비전은 미스터을했습니다 기억 이동하고있다
early for work was trying to model the three the shape of the object now we're
작업 초기에 지금 우리가하고있는 세에게 물체의 형상을 모델링하기 위해 노력했다
shifting to recognizing what the object is the little bit about can we really
우리가 정말 개체에 대한 약간이 무엇인지 인식을 할 수 있습니다 이동
reconstruct these phases or not there's a whole branch of computer vision
이러한 단계를 재구성 여부를 컴퓨터 비전의 전체 분기있다
graphics step continue to work on that but a big part of computer vision is not
그래픽은 그 작업을 계속 단계하지만 컴퓨터 비전의 큰 부분은 아니다
at this time around the turn of the century is focusing on recognition
세기의 전환기 주위에이 시간에 인식에 초점을 맞추고있다
that's bringing computer vision and today the most important parts of the
즉, 컴퓨터 비전과 오늘에게 가장 중요한 부분을 가져이다
computer vision work is focused these cognitive questions like recognition and
컴퓨터 비전 작업이 인식 등이인지 질문을 집중하고,
I questions
내가 질문
another very important piece of work is starting to focus on features so around
작품의 또 다른 매우 중요한 부분 때문에 주위의 기능에 초점을 시작
the time of face recognition people start to realize it's really really hard
사람들이 그것을 실현하기 시작 얼굴 인식의 시간은 정말 열심히 정말
to recognize an object by describing the whole thing like I just said you know I
난 그냥 말했듯이 모든 일을 설명하여 객체를 인식하는 당신은 내가 알고
see you guys were heavily on concluded I don't see the rest of your torso I
너희가 많이 있었다 나는 당신의 몸통 I의 나머지 부분을 볼 수 없습니다 결론을 내렸다 참조
really don't see any of your legs on it in the first row but I recognize you and
정말 첫 번째 행에에 다리 중 하나를 볼 수 있지만 나는 당신을 인식하지 않고
i ke fir you as an object so some people start to realize she is fun this is
나는 그래서 어떤 사람들은 그녀가 이것이 재미 실현하기 위해 시작 개체로 전나무 당신을 애
really a global shape now we have to go after in order to recognize an object
정말 글로벌 형상은 지금 우리가 물체를 인식하기 위해 후 가야
maybe it's the features if we recognize the important features an object we can
우리는 중요한 기능을 우리가 할 수있는 객체를 인식하는 경우 아마이 기능의
go a long way and makes a lot of sense
먼 길을 가서 많은 이해
think about evolution if you are out hunting you don't need to recognize that
당신이 밖으로 것을 인식 할 필요가 없습니다 당신을 사냥하는 경우 진화에 대해 생각
Tigers full body in shape to decide you need to run away you know there's a few
모양 호랑이 몸 전체는 몇이 알고 도망 할 필요가 결정하는
patches of the first of the tiger through the
관통 호랑이의 첫 번째 패치
leaves probably cool arm you enough so so we need to listen as quick
우리가 빨리 듣고 필요가 너무 있도록 충분히 아마 멋진 팔을 잎
decision-making baseball's version is really quick
의사 결정 야구의 버전은 정말 빠르다
a lot of this happens online important features so this will cost shift by
이에 의해 이동 비용을 부담해야하므로이 많은 온라인 중요한 기능을 발생
David low again you saw that name again is about learning important important
데이비드 낮은 다시 다시 그 이름을보고 중요한 중요한 학습에 관한 것입니다
features on an object and once you learn these important features just a few of
객체에 기능과 당신은 단지 몇 이러한 중요한 기능을 배우면
them on the object you can actually recommends this object in a totally
당신이 할 수있는 개체에 대한 그들 실제로 완전히에이 객체를 권장합니다
different and go on the tolling cluttered scenes so up to keep learnings
다른과 교훈을 유지하도록하도록 징수 복잡 장면에 이동
research election in 2010 or 2012 for about 10 years the entire field of
약 10 년 전 필드의 2010 년 또는 2012 년 연구 선거
computer vision was focusing on using these features to build models to
컴퓨터 비전에 모델을 구축하기 위해 이러한 기능을 사용하는 방법에 초점을 맞추고 있었다
recognize objects and scenes and we've done a great job we've gone a long way
객체 및 장면을 인식하고 우리는 우리가 먼 길을 갔어요 훌륭한 일을 했어
one of the reasons deep learning that word was became more more convincing to
깊은 그 단어를 배우는 이유 중 하나는 더 이상 설득력이되었다
a lot of people is we will see that the features that a deep learning that
많은 사람들이 우리가 볼 수있는 기능은 그 깊은 학습이 그
learners is very similar to these engineered features by brilliant
학습자는 화려한하여 이러한 설계 기능과 매우 유사
engineers so it kind of confirmed even know you know if needed we needed them
엔지니어는 필요한 경우 우리가 그들을 필요 알지 심지어 종류의 확인 있도록
below to first tell us this features work and then we start to develop better
아래 먼저이 일을 갖추고 있으며, 우리는 더 나은 개발을 시작하는 우리에게 얘기를
mathematical models to learn these features by itself but they confirmed
수학적 모델은 그 자체로 이러한 기능을 배울 수 있지만 확인
each other so so the historical you know importance of this work should not be
서로 너무 너무 역사적 당신은 안이 작품의 중요성을 알고
diminished this work is the intellectual foundation for us one of the
감소 된이 작품은 우리의 지적 기반의 하나입니다
intellectual foundation for us to realize that how critical or how useful
우리의 지적 기반은 실현하기 위해 얼마나 중요한지 또는 얼마나 유용한 지 그
these deep learning features are where we learn them just briefly say because
이러한 깊은 학습 기능은 우리가 그들을 배울 경우 그냥 간단히 때문에 말할 수 있습니다
of the features that have a low and many other researchers told us we can't use
이 기능의 저와 다른 많은 연구자들은 우리가 사용할 수없는 우리에게
that to to learn scene recognition and around that time the machine learning
그 장면 인식과 그 시간 기계 학습 주위를 배울합니다
tools we use mostly is either graphical models or support vector machine and
도구는 우리가 주로 사용하거나 그래픽 모델 또는 지원 벡터 기계와
this is one influential work on using support vector machine and colonel
이 하나의 영향력 작업 지원 벡터 기계와 대령을 사용하여에
models 2222 recognizes thing but I'll be brief here and last deep learning model
모델 2222은 일을 인식하지만 난 여기에 간단한과 마지막 깊은 학습 모델이 될 수 있습니다
is this feature or feature baseball called deformable part Waldo is where we
이 기능 또는 기능 야구라는 변형 부분은 왈도입니다입니다 우리
learn parts of object like parts of the person and we learn how they come figure
사람의 일부처럼 개체의 일부를 배우고 우리는 그들이 그림을 오는 방법
each other income figure in space used a support vector machine kind of model to
공간에서 서로 소득 그림에 모델을 지원 벡터 머신의 종류를 사용
recognize objects like humans and bottles around this time that's 2009
2009 년의이시기에 인간과 병 같은 객체를 인식
2010 the field of computer vision is mature enough that we're working on this
2010 년 컴퓨터 비전 분야는 우리가 최선을 다하고 충분히 성숙
important on the heart probably recognize the pedestrians and
중요한 심장이 아마 보행자 인식과
recognizing cars they're no longer contrived problem something else was
더 이상 인위적인 문제가 뭔가있어 차를 인식하지 것은 다른 사람이었다
needed his bench partly because as a field advancing now if we don't have
때문에 우리가하지 않으면 지금 진행 필드로 부분적으로 자신의 벤치가 필요
good benchmark then everybody feels set of images and it's really hard to really
좋은 벤치 마크는 다음 모두가 이미지 집합 느낌과 정말 열심히 정말
set global standard so one of the most important benchmark is called pass goal
가장 중요한 기준 중 하나가 통과 목표라고 있도록 글로벌 표준을 설정
V oc object recognition bench part its bio European it's a european effort that
V OC는 물체 인식 벤치 일부는 유럽의 노력 유럽 생물의 그
researchers put together by tens of thousands of images from 20 classes of
연구진은 20 종류의 이미지 수만에 의해 함께 넣어
optics and these are one example per per object like cats cults cows movie no
광학 및이 고양이처럼 하나의 예 개체 당 기준 요금은 소 영화를 숭배하지
cats dogs cows airplanes bottles
고양이는 소 비행기 병 개
horses trained
말 훈련
and Aldous and then we used and then annually our computer vision researchers
다음 더스와 우리는 매년 우리의 컴퓨터 비전 연구자를 사용
and laps come to compete all the object recognition task for best girl object
그리고 바퀴는 최고의 여자 객체에 대한 모든 물체 인식 작업을 경쟁 올
recognition challenge and an over the past you know like through the years the
당신이 년을 통해처럼 알고 과거를 통해 인식 문제와
the performance just keeps increasing and that was when we start to feel
성능은 계속 증가하고 우리가 느끼기 시작할 때
excited about the progress of the field at that time
그 때의 필드의 진행 흥분
here's a little bit over more closer story close to us is that my love of my
여기에 가까운 우리에게 더 가까이 이야기를 통해 조금이다 그건 그 내 사랑 내
students were thinking you know the real world is not about 20 objects the real
학생들은 현실 세계가 진짜 약 20 개체를 알고 생각했다
world is a little more than 20 optics so following the work of Pasco visual
세상은 그렇게 파스코 시각의 작품 다음 작은 20 개 이상의 광학입니다
object recognition challenge we put together this massive massive project
물체 인식 문제는 우리가 함께이 방대한 대규모 프로젝트를 넣어
image that some of you may have heard of image that in this class you will be
여러분 중 일부는이 클래스에서 당신이 될 것 이미지 들었을 수 있다는 이미지
using the tiny portion of the image that in some of your assignment that image
이미지의 작은 부분을 사용하여 해당 과제 그 이미지의 일부에
that is the data set of 50 million images all cleaned my hands and
그 모두가 내 손을 청소하고 5 천만 이미지의 데이터 세트입니다
annotated over 20,000 object classes to students who cleaned it
그것을 청소 학생들에게 20,000 객체 클래스를 주석
various areas of my life remove the crowdsourcing platform of the habits of
내 삶의 다양한 영역의 습관의 크라우드 소싱 플랫폼을 제거
that Gladys dunno also suffered from you know putting together this this platform
당신이 함께이 플랫폼이 퍼팅 알고에서 글래디스는 고통을 몰라 그
but it's a very exciting day does not we started we started to put together
그러나 그것은 매우 흥미로운 일 우리가 함께 넣어하기 시작 시작되지 않습니다이다
competitions annually called image that competition for object recognition and
대회는 매년 이미지라고 그 물체 인식을위한 경쟁
for example a standard competition of image classification by Imogen that is a
예를 들어 이모 겐에 의한 영상 분류의 표준 경쟁은은이다
thousand object classes over almost 1.5 million images and algorithms compete on
거의 150 만 이미지와 알고리즘을 통해 천 개체 클래스에 경쟁
the performance so actually I just heard somebody who was on the social media was
성능은 그래서 사실 난 그냥 소셜 미디어에 있던 사람이 들었어요
referring image that challenges the Olympics of computer vision I was very
나는 매우했다 컴퓨터 비전의 올림픽 도전 이미지 참조
flattering
유망한
bringing us close to the history making the people are so so that challenge 2010
그 도전 2010 그래서 그렇게 사람들을 역사에 우리가 가까이 가져
that's actually around the time pass go you know where their colleagues they
그 시간 패스 주위에 실제로 것은 어디 동료를 알아가는 사람들
told us they're gonna start to phase out their challenge of 20 object so we face
그들은 우리가 직면 그래서 20 개체의 자신의 문제를 단계적으로 폐지하는 거 처음이야 우리에게 말했다
in the thousand object images a challenge and why accesses error rate
천 개체의 이미지에 도전하는 이유는 에러율에 액세스
and we start to we started with very significant error and of course you know
우리는 매우 중요한 오류와 함​​께 시작에 우리는 시작 물론 당신은 알고있다
every year that decreased but there is a particularly years really decreased it
매년 감소하지만 특히 세 정말 감소가 그
was cutting hot almost is 2012 2012 is the year that the winning architecture
올해는 뜨거운 거의 IS 2012 2012입니다 절단 한 것 승리 아키텍처
of image that challenge was a convolution on your network I will talk
이미지 그 문제는 내가 말할 것 네트워크의 회선이었다
about it was not invented in 2012 despite how all the new speaker's felt
그것은 어떻게 모든 새로운 스피커의 느낌에도 불구하고 2012 년에 발명되지 않았습니다 대해
like it's the newest thing around the block it's not it was invented back in
이 블록 주위에 새로운 일이처럼 그것은 다시 발명되었다 아니에요
the seventies and eighties
칠십 년대와 80 년대
he's but having a convergence of things will talk about convolution on your
그는 그러나 사물의 융합에 회선에 대해 이야기합니다 보내고 당신의
network showed its massive power as a high capacity and to end training
네트워크는 대용량으로 그 거대한 힘을 보여 주었다 훈련을 종료
architecture and Wang the image that challenged by a huge margin and that was
큰 차이로 제치고 그였다 이미지 아키텍처와 왕
quite a historical moment from a a mathematical point of view it wasn't
보기의 AA 수학적 관점에서 매우 역사적인 순간이 아니었다 그것은
that new before my engineering and and solving real-world point of view this
볼이 내 엔지니어링 전에 새로운 및 해결 실제 포인트가
was a historical moment that piece of work was covered by you know numerous
당신이 많은 알고에 의해 작품의 조각이 덮여있는 역사적 순간이었다
times and all this this is the onset this is the beginning of learning
시간이 모든 문제는이 발병입니다 학습의 시작입니다
revolution if you call it and this is the premise of this class so at this
혁명 당신은 그것을 호출이 이것 때문에이 클래스의 전제 인 경우
point I'm gonna switch so we went through a brief history of computer
우리가 컴퓨터의 간단한 역사를 통해 갔다, 그래서 나는 거 스위치 해요 가리
vision for 540 million years
540,000,000년 비전
overview of this class is there any other question
이 클래스의 개요 다른 질문이 있습니다
alright so we're talking even though it was kind of overwhelming we talked a lot
우리가 많이 얘기 종류의 압도적 이었지만 확실히 그래서 우리는 심지어 얘기
about finding different task in computer vision seems to 31 and is going to focus
컴퓨터 비전에서 다른 작업을 찾는 것에 대해 31에 보인다 초점을 맞출 것입니다
on the visual recognition problem also enlarged especially through most of the
시각적 인식 문제에도 특히 대부분의를 통해 확대
foundation lecture
기초 강좌
classification but now you know everything we talk about is gonna be
우리가 얘기 분류하지만 지금은 당신이 알고있는 모든 것을 할 거입니다
based on that image that classification set up we will we were getting to other
우리는 우리가 다른 얻고 있었다됩니다 설정 분류 그 이미지를 기반으로
visual recognition scenarios but the image classification problem is the main
시인성 시나리오이지만, 화상 분류 문제이다 메인
problem we will focus on Emma's class which means please keep in mind
명심하십시오 의미 우리는 엠마의 클래스에 초점을 맞출 것이다 문제
visual recognition is not just image classification right there was 3d
시각적 인식은 바로 3 차원 거기에 그냥 이미지 분류되지 않습니다
modeling there was a grouping of segmentation and all this but that's
모델링이 분할의 그룹이었다하고 있지만,이 모든입니다
that's what we'll focus on and I don't need to call miss you that just even
그건 우리가에 초점을 맞출 것이다 나는 미스 당신이 그냥 전화도 할 필요가 없습니다 것
application wise image classification is extremely useful problem
애플리케이션 현명한 이미지 분류는 매우 유용 문제
from you know big big commercial Internet companies a point of view to
당신은 큰 큰 상업적인 인터넷 기업들에게 관점을 알고부터
startup ideas you know you want to recognize objects you want to recognize
시작 아이디어 당신은 당신이 인식 할 객체를 인식 할 알고
food do online shop mobile shopping you want us torture albums so you move
음식은 이동할 수 있도록 당신이 우리에게 고문 앨범을 원하는 온라인 상점 모바일 쇼핑을
classification news is is can be a bread-and-butter task for many many
분류 소식은 많은 많은에 대한 생계 작업이 될 수있다
important problems there is a problem that's related to two classification and
중요한 문제 두 분류와 관련이있어 문제가있다
today I don't expect you to understand the differences but I wanted to hear
오늘은 당신이 차이를 이해하는 기대하지 않는다 그러나 나는 듣고 싶어
that while this class will make sure you learn to understand the nuances in the
이 클래스가 있는지 확인 반면 것을 당신은의 미묘한 차이를 이해하는 법을 배워야
the details of different flavors of visual recognition what is image
시각적 인식의 다른 맛의 세부 내용 이미지
classification what's object detection what's image captioning and these have
분류는 영상 자막이 그리고 이것들이 가지고있는 물체 감지 무엇
different flavors for example you know while he made two classification my
그는이 분류를 만든 예를 들어 다른 맛을 알고 내
focus on the whole big image object detection by tell you where things
로 전체의 큰 이미지 객체 검출에 초점 곳 가지를 알려
exactly are like where the car is the pedestrian
정확히 차가 보행자입니다 같다
the hammer and the word that the relationship between objects and so on
망치와 단어가 등등 객체와의 관계
social their nuances and details that you will be learning about in this class
이 클래스에 대해 학습한다 그들의 뉘앙스 및 세부 사항을 사회
and I already said CNN or coalition on your network is one type of deeply
나는 이미 CNN 말했다 또는 네트워크의 연합은 깊이의 한 종류입니다
architecture but it's the overwhelmingly successful the planning architecture and
아키텍처하지만 계획 아키텍처 압도적으로 성공이고
this is the architecture we will be focusing on and to just go back to the
이것은 우리가 집중되고 단지로 다시 이동합니다 아키텍처
image 9 challenge so I said the historical year is 2012 this is the year
이미지 9 도전은 그래서 역사적 년이는 연도 2012 인
I'll excursion Jeff Hinton proposed this this convolutional I think it's a seven
나는 그것이 칠 생각 제프 힌튼이이 길쌈을 제안 소풍 있습니다
layer convolutional your network to win the image that challenge model before
이전 모델에 도전 이미지를 승리 네트워크 길쌈 층
this year
올해
a SIFT feature plus support vector machine architecture it still hierarchy
기능을 SIFT 플러스 벡터 머신 아키텍처 그것은 여전히​​ 계층 구조를 지원
but it doesn't have that flavor of and two and learning fast forward to 2015
하지만 두의 맛을 가지고 2015 년에 앞으로 빠른 학습하지 않습니다
the winning architecture is still a conclusion you're not worried it's a
승리 아키텍처는 아직도 당신이 그것의 걱정하지 않은 결론이다
hunter 51 layers buy buy microsoft Asia research researchers and it's clear
사냥꾼 (51) 층은 마이크로 소프트 아시아 연구소 연구원을 구입 구입하고 그것은 분명
reason the residual that the residual that so I'm not so sure you for a cover
이유가 잔류 잔류 그래서 커버에 대한 확신 아니에요
that definitely don't expect to to know every single layer what they do actually
그 확실히 실제로 무엇을 하나 하나 층 알고 기대하지 않습니다
they repeat itself at heart but every year since 2012 the winning architecture
그들은 2012 우승 구조 때문에 마음 만 매년 자체를 반복
of images that challenge is a deep learning based architecture so like I
이미지의 그 문제는 내가 같은 깊은 학습 기반의 아키텍처입니다
said I also want you to respect history is not invented overnight there is a lot
나는 또한 당신이 역사는 발명되지 존중하고 싶은 것을하는 것은 하룻밤 많이있다
of influential players today but you know there are a lot of people who build
오늘하지만 당신이 알고있는 영향력있는 선수의 구축 많은 사람들이있다
a foundation I actually I don't have the slides one important thing to remember
기초 사실 나는 슬라이드를 기억해야 할 한 가지 중요한 일이 없습니다
is Kunihiko Fukushima contigo solution was a Japanese scientist who build a
쿠니히코 후쿠시마 contigo 솔루션은 구축 일본의 과학자했다입니다
model corneil Kong the truck and that was the beginning of the newer network
모델 corneil 홍콩 트럭 및 그 새로운 네트워크의 시작
architecture and yellow color is also a very influential person and he's really
건축과 노란색 색상도 매우 영향력있는 사람이며 그는 정말
the the groundbreaking work in my opinion of young coup was published in
젊은 쿠데타의 내 의견에 혁신적인 작업에 출판되었다
the nineteen nineties so that's one mathematicians which Jeff Hinton
그래서 19 구십 한 수학자의 한 제프 힌튼
all-inclusive adviser was involved worked out the back propagation learning
포함 된 모든 항목을 포함 고문은 다시 전파 학습을했다
strategy which if this were deleting anything under will tell you in a couple
아래에 아무것도 삭제이 있다면 전략은 몇 당신을 말할 것이다
of weeks but but the the mathematical mando was roughed up in the eighties and
주하지만,하지만, 수학적 만도는 80 년대 거칠게하고,
the
그만큼
undies and this was your local was working for Bell Labs it AT&T which is
속옷이 있었다 그것이 AT & T 벨 연구소에서 근무하고 해당 지역의
amazing place at that time there's no bail UPS today anymore that they were
그 때 놀랄만한 장소들이 있다고 더 이상 오늘날에는 보석 UPS가 없습니다
working on really ambitious projects and he needed to recognize the digits
정말 야심 찬 프로젝트를 진행하고 그는 숫자를 인식하는 데 필요한
because even to leave that product was shipped to our bags in the USA post
심지어 미국의 게시물에 우리의 가방에 제공된 해당 제품을 떠나 있기 때문에
office to recognize difficult and checks and kinky constructive those coalition
사무실은 어렵고 검사 및 변태 건설하는 연합을 인식하는
on your network and this is where he he's inspired by Hubel and Wiesel he
그는 그가 HUBEL과 위젤 그는 영감을 어디 네트워크에서이입니다
starts by looking at some pool edge like structures and image it's not like the
일부 수영장에서 찾고 의해 시작은 구조와 같은 가장자리와 이미지는이 마음에 들지있어
whole letter eight it's really needs to edges and the layer-by-layer
전체 편지 정말 가장자리에 필요가있어 팔과 계층 별 층
filters these edges pull them together filters pool and then the field this
이 가장자리를 끌어 필터들 함께 풀을 필터링 한 다음 필드이
architecture 20121 Alex kruschev ski and Jeff Hinton you almost exactly the thing
아키텍처 20121 알렉스 kruschev 스키와 제프 힌튼하면 거의 정확하게 일
architecture to participate in the car
아키텍처는 차에 참여
imagine a challenge there is a few changes but that become the winning
몇 가지 변경이 도전을 상상하지만 승리가 될
architecture of this so we'll tell you more about the detail changes at the lib
이 아키텍처는 그래서 우리는 lib 디렉토리의 세부 사항 변경에 대한 자세한 말씀 드리죠
capacity model did grow a little bit because Moore's Law helped us there's
거기에 무어의 법칙이 우리를 도왔 때문에 용량 모델은 조금 증가했다
also a very very detailed function that change the little bit of a shape for
대한 모양의 약간의 변화도 매우 매우 상세한 기능
most Signori 224 but to file in their shape but whatever there's a couple of
대부분의 Signori (224)는 그 형태하지만 무엇에 파일뿐만 몇있다
small changes but really by large nothing had changed
큰 아무것도에 의해 정말 작은 변화 만 변경했다
mathematically but important things did change and that grow deep learning
수학적하지만 중요한 것은 변화 않았고 그 깊은 학습을 성장
Architektur black ink crew into its Renaissance one is like a morsel and
그 르네상스 하나에 Architektur 검정 잉크 승무원은 음식물의 한 입처럼이며,
hardware hardware made a huge difference because these are high extremely high
이들은 매우 높은 높은 있기 때문에 하드웨어 하드웨어는 큰 차이를 만들어
capacity models one dela Cruz
용량 모델 일 델라 크루즈
this painfully slow because of the the bottleneck of computation he couldn't
때문에 계산의 병목이 고통스럽게 느린 그는 할 수 없었다
build this model too big a while so you cannot be added to big cannot fully
그래서 당신은 큰 수없는 완벽에 추가 할 수는 없지만이 모델에게 너무 큰 구축
realize its potential for machine learning standpoint there's over 15 and
15 이상 거기에 기계 학습의 관점에 대한 잠재력을 실현하고
all these problems you can also but now we have much faster bigger transistor
이러한 모든 문제는 당신도하지만 지금 우리는 훨씬 더 빨리 더 큰 트랜지스터를 가질 수있다
transistor microchips and GPUs from Nvidia made a huge difference in deep
엔비디아에서 트랜지스터 마이크로 칩 및 GPU는 깊은에 큰 차이를 만들어
learning history that we can now trainees models in a reasonable amount
우리가 지금 적당한 양의 모델을 연수생 수있는 학습의 역사
of time even if they're huge and others I think we do need to take her out of
그들은 거대한이고 다른 사람들이 우리가 밖으로 데리고해야합니까 생각하는 경우에도 시간
work is data availability of data that was the big data did a self is just you
작품 자체가 그냥있는 빅 데이터했던이었다 데이터의 데이터 가용성이다
know it doesn't mean anything if you don't know how to use it but in this
그것은 아무것도 의미하지 않는다 알고는 있지만 그것을 사용하는 방법을 모르는 경우
deep learning Architektur data become the driving force for high-capacity
깊은 학습 Architektur 데이터 고용량 구동력 될
model to enable the doin training true true true help avoid overfitting when
모델은 뭐하는 교육을 활성화하는 진정한 진정한 진정한 도움 피하기 overfitting 때
you have enough data so you know so you if you look at the number of pixels that
당신은 픽셀 수를 보면 당신은 그래서 당신을 알 수 있도록 당신은 충분한 데이터를 가지고 그
machine learning people had in 2012 versus helical having 1998 it's a huge
기계 학습 사람들은 나선형 그것이 거대 1998를 가진 대 2012 년에 있었다
difference
차이
orders of magnitude so so that was so this is the focus of 231
크기의 주문은 그래서 그래서 그래서이 (231)의 초점이었다
but will also go oh it's also important one last time I'm drooling this idea
뿐만 아니라 갈 것입니다 오, 내가이 생각을 침을 흘리고있어 중요한 마지막이기도
that visual intelligence does go beyond object recognition I don't want any of
나는 어떤을 원하지 않는 시각적 지능 물체 인식을 넘어 않습니다
you coming out of this course dinky we've done everything you know we've
이 과정에서 나오는 것은 우리는 당신이 우리가했습니다 알고있는 모든 일을했습니다 딩키
challenged do flying the entire space of visual recognition it's not true there
시각적 인식의 전체 공간을 비행 할 도전은이 사실이 아니에요
are still a lot of cool problems to solve for example you know does labeling
여전히 멋진 많은 문제가 당신이 알고 예를 들어 해결하는 것은 라벨링을한다
entire scene with perceptual grouping so I know where every single pixel belonged
모든 단일 픽셀이 속한 곳 지각 그룹과 전체 장면은 그래서 나는 알고있다
to
에
that's still ongoing problem combining
그 여전히 함께 지속적인 문제입니다
recognition with 3d is a really there's a lot of excitement happening at the
3 차원으로 인식이 정말 흥분을 많이가 거기 무슨 일이 일어나고입니다
intersection of vision and robotics this is this is definitely one area of that
비전과는이이 로봇의 교차로는 그 확실히 하나의 영역입니다
and then anything to do with motion of borders and and and and this is another
다음 아무것도 국경의 움직임과와와 함께 할 수있는이 또 다른입니다
big open area of research work you know beyond just gonna sing you actually want
당신은 그냥 거 이상으로 알고 연구 작업의 큰 개방 영역은 당신이 실제로 원하는 노래
deeply understand the victor
깊이 승자를 이해
what people are doing what are the relationship between objects in the West
어떤 사람들이하고있는 것은 서양의 개체 사이의 관계 무엇인가
Rd into the the the relation between objects and this is an ongoing project
객체 사이의 상기 관계에 RD와이 진행중인 프로젝트
called visual genome in my lap that just in the number of my students are
학생들의 수는 단지 내 무릎에 시각적 게놈이라고
involved and this goes far beyond image classification of weed we talked about
관련이 지금까지 우리가에 대한 이야기​​ 잡초의 이미지 분류 넘어
and what is one of our Holy Grails while one of the Holy Grails of community this
우리의 거룩한 Grails에의 한 것입니다 사회 이것의 성배의 일 동안
to be able to tell the story of a scene right so I think about you as a human
바로 그래서 인간으로 당신에 대해 생각하는 장면의 이야기를 할 수 있어야합니다
you open your eyes
당신은 당신의 눈을 열어
the moment you open your eyes you're able to describe what you see in fact in
당신은 당신이 할 수있어 눈을 뜨고 순간 당신이 실제로 무엇을보고 설명하기
psychology experiments we find that even if you show people this picture for only
심리학 실험은 우리는 당신이 사람들에게 단에 사진을 표시하는 경우에도 발견
five hundred milliseconds that's literally half of the second people who
말 그대로 두 번째 사람의 절반이다 오백 밀리 자
write essays about it we pay them $10 an hour so they didn't
그들은하지 않았다, 그래서 그것에 대해 에세이를 작성 우리는 그들에게 $ 시간당 10을 지불
it wasn't that long but you know I figure if we talked more money they
그것은 그 길지 않았다하지만 우리는 더 많은 돈을 이야기하면 당신은 내가 그림을 알고 그들이
probably could write longer ethics but the point is that our visual system is
아마 더 이상 윤리를 작성하지만 요점은 우리의 시각 시스템이 있다는 것입니다 수
extremely powerful we can tell stories and I would dream of this is my cell is
매우 강력한 내 셀입니다 우리는 이야기를하고 나는이 꿈을 꿀 것
to undress dissertation that we give you give a computer one picture per and
논문을 옷을 위해 우리는 당신이 당 컴퓨터 한 그림을 제공주고 있고
outcomes
결과
description like this you know I was getting there you'll see that give the
이 같은 설명 당신은 당신이이 줄이 표시됩니다 내가 거기에 도착하고 있었다 알고
khmer Olympic tur gives you one sentence or you give the number one pick turned
크메르어 올림픽 TUR 당신에게 한 문장을 제공하거나 하나의 선택이 켜져 수가 줄
into a short sentences but we're not here yet but that's one of the holder
하지만 짧은 문장으로 우리는 아직 여기 아니에요하지만 홀더 중 하나
blue and the other holding growth is continuing this continue this i think is
블루와 다른 들고 성장 내가 생각이이 계속이 작업을 계속하고있다
is summarized really well by Audrey's blog is you know like this right there
오드리의 블로그가 정말 잘 요약하면 바로 다음과 같이 알고있다
is refined there so much nuance in this picture that you get to enjoy not only
당신이뿐만 아니라 즐길 얻을이 그림이 너무 많은 뉘앙스를 정제
you recognize the global seek it will be very boring old computer can tell you is
전역은 매우 지루한 오래된 컴퓨터가 당신이 말할 수있을 것입니다 그것을 추구 인식
that room room scale
객실에 객실 규모
whatever type in the locker that's it you know here you recognize what they
그것의 사물함에서 어떤 유형의 당신은 당신이 인식 여기 알고있는 그들은
are recognized the trick
트릭을 인식하고 있습니다
Obama is do you recognize the kind of interaction you recognize the humor you
오바마 대통령은 당신이 유머를 인식 상호 작용의 종류를 인식 할 것입니다
recognize there's just so much knew that this is one of the world is about we
너무 많이 알고,이 세상의 하나입니다 우리에 관한 것입니다 거기에 인식
used our ability to visual nurse tending to not only survive navigate when they
때뿐만 아니라 탐색 생존하는 경향이 시각 간호사에게 우리의 능력을 사용
play but we use it to socialize to entertain to understand the world and
재생 그러나 우리가 세계를 이해하기 위해 즐겁게 교제하는 데 사용
this is where vision in all the book read goals of vision that is so and I
모든 책의 비전은 비전의 목표를 읽을 곳은 그래서 나는 점이다
don't need to convince you that computer visual technology will make our world a
우리의 세계 a를 만들 것이다 당신에게 해당 컴퓨터 시각 기술을 설득 할 필요가 없습니다
better place despite some scary talks out there you know even though you home
당신이 집 심지어하지만 알고 거기 어떤 무서운 이야기에도 불구하고 더 나은 곳으로
today in the industry as well as research world we're using computer
업계에서 오늘뿐만 아니라 연구의 세계 우리가 컴퓨터를 사용하는
vision to build better robots to save lives to go deep exploring analyst now
더 나은 로봇을 구축하는 비전은 이제 분석을 탐험 깊이 갈 생명을 저장합니다
ok so I have like what two minutes 35 minutes left
확인 그래서 나는 35 분 왼쪽 무엇 이분처럼이
great time let me introduce the team and justice are the color instructors with
좋은 시간은 컬러 강사가 나를 팀과 정의를 소개하자
me tienes please stand up to say hi to him
내가 그에게 인사 일어 서서하시기 바랍니다 그래야 될지도
can you like this safe your name quickly and you're like what you just don't give
당신은 빨리이 안전하게 이름을 좋아하고 당신은 그냥 포기하지 않는 것 같아 수 있습니다
a speech but yes
연설 그러나 예
because because people class action and help us to process I respect a person is
사람들의 집단 소송이 우리를 도와 때문에 처리하기 때문에 사람이 존중
confidential personal issues but again I'm going on our terms and leave for a
기밀 개인적인 문제가 다시 나는 우리의 조건에 예정하고 떠날거야하지만,
few weeks starting the end of January social please if you decide you just
월 말부터 몇 주 사회 당신은 당신을 결정하십시오
want to send email to me unless somebody like you they will take
당신 같은 사람이 그들이 취할 것입니다하지 않는 한 나에게 이메일을 보내려면
I'm likely to a reply you promptly sorry about that
그것에 대해 내가 답장 가능성이있어 당신을 즉시 죄송합니다
priorities
우선 순위
about our philosophy and we're not getting to the details we really want
우리의 철학에 대한 그리고 우리는 우리가 진정으로 원하는 세부에 도착하지 않는
this to be a very hands-on project this is really I give a lot of credit to
이것은이 정말 내가 신용을 많이하는 줄 매우 실제적인 프로젝트를 할 수
Justin and Andre they are extremely good at walking through these hands-on
저스틴과 앙드레는 이러한 실습을 통해 걷기에 매우 좋은
details with you so that when you come out of this class you not only have I
이 클래스 나올 때와 세부 있도록뿐만 아니라 I에게 있습니다
love understanding but you have a you have a really good ability to to build
이해를 사랑하지만 당신이 가지고 당신은 구축 할 수있는 정말 좋은 능력을 가지고
your own deep learning code we want you to be exposed to state of the art
자신의 깊은 학습 코드 우리는 당신이 예술의 상태로 노출 할
material you're gonna be learning things really that's as freshest 2015 and it'll
당신이거야 일을 학습 할 수있는 재료 정말 2015로 신선한 그리고 그것은거야
be fun you get to do things like this
이 같은 일을하는 재미를 얻을 수
not not all the time but like time the picture into one goal or or this weird
아니 모든 시간이 있지만, 하나의 목표 나 또는이 이상으로 시간과 같은 사진
thing it'll be a fun class in addition to all the important tasks you you you
일이 모든 중요한 작업에 추가하여 재미 클래스를 알 수있을 것입니다 당신이 당신
you learn we do have grading policies these are all on our website another
당신은 우리가 이러한 다른 웹 사이트에 있습니다 등급을 매기는 정책을 수행 배우
eatery those again one very clear you are grown ups which grew to like
다시 사람들을 식당 하나 당신이 좋아하는 성장 업을 성장 명확
grown-ups we do not take anything at the end of the course is my professors want
우리가 과정의 끝에서 아무것도하지 않는 어른들 내 교수 원하는이다
me to go to this conference and I have to have like three more late they say no
날이 회의에 가서 내가 세처럼이 있어야 더 늦게 그들은 아무 말도
you are responsible for using your total eight days you have 7 late you can use
당신은 당신이 7 늦게 사용할 수있는 사용에 대한 책임 총 팔일 있습니다
them in whatever way you all 10 penalty be all those you have to take a penalty
어떤 방법으로 당신은 모든 10 처벌은 벌금을해야 모든 일
is like really really exceptional medical family emergency
정말 정말 뛰어난 의료 가족 비상 같다
talk to us on the individual basis but anything else
개별 기준으로하지만, 무엇에 우리 이야기
conference that why other finally you know like missing cat or whatever is
회의는 왜 다른 사람은 마침내 당신이 누락 고양이 또는 무엇처럼 알고
we we we we budgeted that into the seven days another his honor cold this is one
우리는 우리가 우리가 칠일에이 하나의 또 다른 자신의 명예 감기 그 예산을 책정 우리
thing I have to say it with a really straight face you are such a privilege
내가 가진 것은 당신이 그런 권한이 있습니다 정말 진지한 얼굴로 대답
institution you are you are grown ups I want you to be responsible for honor
기관 당신은 당신이 당신이 명예에 대한 책임하려는 어른들되어 있습니다
code every single Stampfer student taking this class should know the other
코드이 수업을 하나 하나 Stampfer 학생은 다른 알아야
co if you don't there's no excuse you should go back
공동 당신이 변명이 없다하지 않으면 당신은 돌아 가야한다
wait a collaboration extremely seriously I almost hate to say that statistically
매우 심각하게 나는 거의 통계적으로 그런 말을 싫어 협력을 기다립니다
given a classless big word Allah have a few cases but I also want you to be an
주어진 계급 큰 단어 알라는 몇 가지 경우가 있지만 나는 또한 당신이되고 싶어요
exceptional class even with a size this big we do not want to see anything that
심지어 크기와 뛰어난 클래스이 큰 우리는 무엇을보고 싶어하지 않는
infringes on Academic Honor Code so read the collaboration policies and risk but
대학 명예 코드를 침해하므로 협력 정책과 위험을 읽을 수는 있지만
that this is really respecting yourself I think with all these prereq you can
이것은 정말 당신이 할 수있는 모든 습득 조건으로 생각하는 자신을 존중하는 것을
you can read it I do with anything I want to say is there any burning
당신은 어떤 굽기가 내가 말하고 싶은 무슨 상관 읽을 수
questions that you feel worth asking yes
당신이 예 물어 가치가 느끼는 질문
ok
그래